<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RaspberryPi on Daniel Silva's blog</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/tags/raspberrypi/</link><description>Recent content in RaspberryPi on Daniel Silva's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.danielssilva.dev/tags/raspberrypi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using RaspberryPi as an Azure agent for Pipelines (Part 2)</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/using-raspberry-pi-as-an-azure-agent-for-pipelines-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/using-raspberry-pi-as-an-azure-agent-for-pipelines-part-2/</guid><description>In the first part of this series, we have seen how we can setup a self hosted agent (in this case on a Raspberry Pi). To recap, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list of things required to do on the target host (this is agnostic to the underlying operating system):
Get the latest agent version available (head to the Azure DevOps website &amp;gt; Project settings &amp;gt; Agent Pools &amp;gt; your pool &amp;gt; new agent &amp;gt; download agent) Extract the file Run the config file and specify: Server URL Your PAT Agent pool Agent name Work folder Run the run file or configure as a service.</description></item><item><title>Using RaspberryPi as an Azure agent for Pipelines (Part 1)</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/using-raspberry-pi-as-an-azure-agent-for-pipelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/using-raspberry-pi-as-an-azure-agent-for-pipelines/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently switched to a DevOps role in a new company. I know some basic DevOps concepts, CI/CD, pipelines, builds, artifacts and so on, but never really laid my hands on it.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a bunch of Microsoft Learn modules related to DevOps and other key components that will be part of my new daily basis.
One that caught my attention was the Host your own build agent in Azure Pipelines, which is a module from the Build applications with Azure DevOps learning path.</description></item><item><title>Remote Sessions and notifications</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/remote-sessions-and-notifications/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/remote-sessions-and-notifications/</guid><description>On my last post, in the very end, I showed you an example of something quite simple that you could do with PowerShell on the RaspberryPi: Show a notification when a LED is left ON.
In this post I will show you how I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to display the notification. This will consist of three sections:
How to display a notification Enabling remote sessions through SSH The final script to display a notification from one device to another Showing a notification 🔗Because @WindosNZ #BurntToast module is awesome, I figured that there was something cool that I could do with it!</description></item><item><title>Getting started with PowerShell (Core) on Raspbian (RaspberryPi)</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/getting-started-with-powershell-core-on-raspbian-raspberrypi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/getting-started-with-powershell-core-on-raspbian-raspberrypi/</guid><description>Around a year ago, I started to investigate about new usages for my Raspberry Pi 3b . I love the Raspberry, a tiny, credit-card-sized SBC capable of running different operating systems, but most of the projects I found that seemed interesting were highly complex (or at least seemed) and used python, a language that I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with. Around the same time, I also started to hear a lot about PowerShell (or maybe it caught my attention because I&amp;rsquo;ve started to use it at my work for simple stuff), as a scripting language mainly used (as far as I knew) to automate tasks.</description></item></channel></rss>