<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SQL on Daniel Silva's blog</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/tags/sql/</link><description>Recent content in SQL on Daniel Silva's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.danielssilva.dev/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automating database backups with Universal Automation and dbatools</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/automating-database-backups-with-universal-automation-and-dbatools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/automating-database-backups-with-universal-automation-and-dbatools/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently read about Universal Automation (UA), by Ironman Software. Among many other functionalities, it offers you the possibility to run background jobs and schedule your scripts to run at certain times. And that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we will be exploring today.
Before we start - Let&amp;rsquo;s understand the product naming 🔗This might sound irrelevant for now, but you will understand in a minute why I&amp;rsquo;m mentioning this.
The first time I heard about an Ironman Software product it was the Universal Dashboard (UD).</description></item><item><title>dbatools is not just for DBAs - Import-DbaCsv</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/dbatools-is-not-just-for-dbas---import-dbacsv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/dbatools-is-not-just-for-dbas---import-dbacsv/</guid><description>The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about dbatools was on its early stages and, although it seemed really interesting, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about PowerShell, nor I had to work with SQL professionally. Moreover, to me it looked like it was &amp;ldquo;focused&amp;rdquo; on helping DBAs (maybe hence its name?). Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve never contributed to the project, I&amp;rsquo;ve always kept an eye on it.
Why do I need it now? Some context 🔗I usually have to analyse logs in order to perform some C#/SQL troubleshooting/debugging/performance tuning.</description></item></channel></rss>