<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PowerShell on Daniel Silva's blog</title><link>blog.danielssilva.dev/tags/powershell/</link><description>Recent content in PowerShell on Daniel Silva's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="blog.danielssilva.dev/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automating database backups with Universal Automation and dbatools</title><link>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/automating-database-backups-with-universal-automation-and-dbatools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/automating-database-backups-with-universal-automation-and-dbatools/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently read about Universal Automation (UA), by Ironman Software. Among many other functionalities, it offers you the possibility to run background jobs and schedule your scripts to run at certain times. And that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we will be exploring today.
Before we start - Let&amp;rsquo;s understand the product naming 🔗This might sound irrelevant for now, but you will understand in a minute why I&amp;rsquo;m mentioning this.
The first time I heard about an Ironman Software product it was the Universal Dashboard (UD).</description></item><item><title>dbatools is not just for DBAs - Import-DbaCsv</title><link>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/dbatools-is-not-just-for-dbas---import-dbacsv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/dbatools-is-not-just-for-dbas---import-dbacsv/</guid><description>The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about dbatools was on its early stages and, although it seemed really interesting, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about PowerShell, nor I had to work with SQL professionally. Moreover, to me it looked like it was &amp;ldquo;focused&amp;rdquo; on helping DBAs (maybe hence its name?). Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve never contributed to the project, I&amp;rsquo;ve always kept an eye on it.
Why do I need it now? Some context 🔗I usually have to analyse logs in order to perform some C#/SQL troubleshooting/debugging/performance tuning.</description></item><item><title>PSConfEU - First time at this event? Let me share something with you</title><link>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/psconfeu-first-time-at-this-event-let-me-share-something-with-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/psconfeu-first-time-at-this-event-let-me-share-something-with-you/</guid><description>PSConfEU is the &amp;ldquo;Europe’s largest PowerShell-themed annual conference!&amp;rdquo;. It covers a lot of different topics and brings professionals from all over the world.
&amp;ldquo;In 2020, we’ll have 350 delegate seats again and 40 international speakers&amp;rdquo;
It has talks about DSC, PowerShell internals, Azure, DevOps, IoT and many other areas.
This conference is simply amazing and I&amp;rsquo;m really happy to announce that I will be speaking! Last year was my first time attending and speaking at a conference outside my country, and PSConfEU was the one.</description></item><item><title>You can now sponsor me on GitHub!</title><link>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/you-can-now-sponsor-me-on-github/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/you-can-now-sponsor-me-on-github/</guid><description>As you might be aware, GitHub launched GitHub Sponsors a while back. The purpose is to provide a way for people to show appreciation towards open source developers, by sponsoring them, by giving money, for their work.
Why is this any different from platforms like PayPal, Patreon, etc? 🔗The good thing about this is that GitHub will match your donations (up to $5k) for the first 12 months. This means that the developer will receive double the amount you contribute with!</description></item><item><title>Remote Sessions and notifications</title><link>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/remote-sessions-and-notifications/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/remote-sessions-and-notifications/</guid><description>On my last post, in the very end, I showed you an example of something quite simple that you could do with PowerShell on the RaspberryPi: Show a notification when a LED is left ON.
In this post I will show you how I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to display the notification. This will consist of three sections:
How to display a notification Enabling remote sessions through SSH The final script to display a notification from one device to another Showing a notification 🔗Because @WindosNZ #BurntToast module is awesome, I figured that there was something cool that I could do with it!</description></item><item><title>Getting started with PowerShell (Core) on Raspbian (RaspberryPi)</title><link>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/getting-started-with-powershell-core-on-raspbian-raspberrypi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>blog.danielssilva.dev/post/getting-started-with-powershell-core-on-raspbian-raspberrypi/</guid><description>Around a year ago, I started to investigate about new usages for my Raspberry Pi 3b . I love the Raspberry, a tiny, credit-card-sized SBC capable of running different operating systems, but most of the projects I found that seemed interesting were highly complex (or at least seemed) and used python, a language that I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with. Around the same time, I also started to hear a lot about PowerShell (or maybe it caught my attention because I&amp;rsquo;ve started to use it at my work for simple stuff), as a scripting language mainly used (as far as I knew) to automate tasks.</description></item></channel></rss>