<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PowerShell on Daniel Silva's blog</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/tags/powershell/</link><description>Recent content in PowerShell on Daniel Silva's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.danielssilva.dev/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get resources missing in Resource Group using PowerShell</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/draft/get-missing-azure-resources-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/draft/get-missing-azure-resources-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently stumbled across a situation where some resource groups were missing a given type of resource.
The &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; scenario is that each resource group has a bunch of resources, and this happens for multiple resource groups owned by my team.
There were some issues with some implementations, and there was no logic on why some resource groups had the resource and others didn&amp;rsquo;t. Since we are talking about hundreds of resource groups, checking one by one is out of question.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automating database backups with Universal Automation and dbatools</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/automating-database-backups-with-universal-automation-and-dbatools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/automating-database-backups-with-universal-automation-and-dbatools/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently read about &lt;a href="https://ironmansoftware.com/universal-automation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Universal Automation (UA)&lt;/a>, by &lt;a href="https://ironmansoftware.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ironman Software&lt;/a>.
Among many other functionalities, it offers you the possibility to run background jobs and schedule your scripts to run at certain times.
And that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we will be exploring today.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="before-we-start---lets-understand-the-product-naming">Before we start - Let&amp;rsquo;s understand the product naming &lt;a href="#before-we-start---lets-understand-the-product-naming" class="anchor">🔗&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>&lt;p>This might sound irrelevant for now, but you will understand in a minute why I&amp;rsquo;m mentioning this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first time I heard about an Ironman Software product it was the &lt;a href="https://docs.universaldashboard.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Universal Dashboard (UD)&lt;/a>.
In the meantime, another product surfaced: Universal Automation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>dbatools is not just for DBAs - Import-DbaCsv</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/dbatools-is-not-just-for-dbas---import-dbacsv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/dbatools-is-not-just-for-dbas---import-dbacsv/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about &lt;a href="https://dbatools.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dbatools&lt;/a> was on its early stages and, although it seemed really interesting, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about PowerShell, nor I had to work with SQL professionally.
Moreover, to me it looked like it was &amp;ldquo;focused&amp;rdquo; on helping DBAs (maybe hence its name?).
Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve never contributed to the project, I&amp;rsquo;ve always kept an eye on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="why-do-i-need-it-now-some-context">Why do I need it now? Some context &lt;a href="#why-do-i-need-it-now-some-context" class="anchor">🔗&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>&lt;p>I usually have to analyse logs in order to perform some C#/SQL troubleshooting/debugging/performance tuning.
The approach that I usually take is to use Excel and import the log file as a table, so that I can filter, highlight and so on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PSConfEU - First time at this event? Let me share something with you</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/psconfeu-first-time-at-this-event-let-me-share-something-with-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/psconfeu-first-time-at-this-event-let-me-share-something-with-you/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://psconf.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PSConfEU&lt;/a> is the &lt;a href="https://psconf.eu/about.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;Europe’s largest PowerShell-themed annual conference!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>.
It covers a lot of different topics and brings professionals from all over the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;In 2020, we’ll have 350 delegate seats again and 40 international speakers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It has talks about DSC, PowerShell internals, Azure, DevOps, IoT and many other areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This conference is simply amazing and I&amp;rsquo;m really happy to announce that I will be speaking!
Last year was my first time attending and speaking at a conference outside my country, and PSConfEU was the one.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t ask for a better experience.
Let me share my experience with you, specially if you are a newcomer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Remote Sessions and notifications</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/remote-sessions-and-notifications/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/remote-sessions-and-notifications/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/getting-started-with-powershell-core-on-raspbian-raspberrypi/">On my last post&lt;/a>, in the very end, I showed you an example of something quite simple that you could do with PowerShell on the RaspberryPi: Show a notification when a LED is left ON.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;p class="markdown-image">
 &lt;img src="https://blog.danielssilva.dev/images/Getting_started_with_PowerShell_Raspberry/notification.png" alt="" />
&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post I will show you how I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to display the notification. This will consist of three sections:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How to display a notification&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enabling remote sessions through SSH&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The final script to display a notification from one device to another&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="showing-a-notification">Showing a notification &lt;a href="#showing-a-notification" class="anchor">🔗&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">Because &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WindosNZ?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WindosNZ&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BurntToast?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BurntToast&lt;/a> module is awesome, I figured that there was something cool that I could do with it! And what&amp;#39;s that? Get current temperature from my &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Raspberry_Pi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Raspberry_Pi&lt;/a> and receive the notification on windows10 machine. EVERYTHING using only &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PowerShell?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#PowerShell&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://t.co/vJCEaoNMqi">pic.twitter.com/vJCEaoNMqi&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting started with PowerShell (Core) on Raspbian (RaspberryPi)</title><link>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/getting-started-with-powershell-core-on-raspbian-raspberrypi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.danielssilva.dev/post/getting-started-with-powershell-core-on-raspbian-raspberrypi/</guid><description>&lt;p>Around a year ago, I started to investigate about new usages for my Raspberry Pi 3b . I love the Raspberry, a tiny, credit-card-sized SBC capable of running different operating systems, but most of the projects I found that seemed interesting were highly complex (or at least seemed) and used python, a language that I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with. Around the same time, I also started to hear a lot about PowerShell (or maybe it caught my attention because I&amp;rsquo;ve started to use it at my work for simple stuff), as a scripting language mainly used (as far as I knew) to automate tasks.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>